Guide to the Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Individuals A-L, Series I
  - Cleary, Edward L.
    - Source files re. Evangelicals in Latin America (Box 443, Folder 24-28)
    - Source files re. Evangelicalism and Fundamentalism in Latin America (Box 443, Folder 29-50)
    - Source files re. Fundamentalism (Box 444, Folder 1-9)
    - Source files re. Protestants in Central America (Box 444, Folder 10-23)
    - Source files re. books by David Stoll and David Martin (Box 444, Folder 24-35)
    - Source files re. Protestantism - Definitions (Box 444, Folder 36-38)
    - Source files re. Pentecostals (Box 444, Folder 39-48)
    - Source files re. Protestant and Pentecostal Missions (Box 444, Folder 49-51)
    - Source files re. Protestantism in Latin America: CELAM and Vatican views (Box 444, Folder 52-59)
    - Source files re. Christianity in Latin America and political involvement (Box 444, Folder 60-61)
    - Source files re. Protestantism and Pentecostals in Latin America (Box 445, Folder 1-49)
    - Source files re. Protestantism and Pentecostals in Latin America (Box 446, Folder 1-15)
    - Source files on Pentecostals, incl. Hispanic, Women (Box 446, Folder 16-21)
    - Source files on Protestantism in Latin America (Box 446, Folder 22-38)
    - Source files for Introduction to Pentecostal book (Power, Politics, and Pentecostals in Latin America, 1997) (Box 446, Folder 39-51)
    - Source files for Chapter 4 of book - re. Pentecostals (Box 447, Folder 1-50)
    - Source files for Chapter 4 of book - re. Pentecostals (Box 448, Folder 1-21)
  - Clift, William Avery
    1817 - Born in Griswold, CT; 1839 - Graduated from Amherst College; 1840-1843 - Attended Union Theological Seminary; 1844 - Ordained Stonington, CT; 1844-64 - pastor in Stonington 1864-1867 - controller Woodlawn Cemetery, N. Y. City; 1869-1878- pastor in Mystic Bridge,CT; 1881-1886 - Hadlyme, CT; 1886-1890 resided in Mystic Bridge, CT.. One of founders and first president American Fish-Culturists Association; 1890 - Died in Mystic Bridge, CT.
    - Private journals: Nine journals written by Clift, 1834-1842 (Box 22)
    - Notebook belonging to Harriet A. Peters, wife of Clift, 1837 (Box 23)
    - Notebook belonging to George D. Clift, son, 1871 (Box 23)
    - Notebook belonging to Myra Clift, granddaughter (Box 23)
    - Personal items and memorabilia: Includes Pastor's handbook, talk to "Gentlemen of Columbia" re. the formation of a fraternity, banquet program, photograph, one letter to Mrs. George Clift (Box 23)
  - Coapman, Verne and Alice
    The Coapmans were American Presbyterian missionaries in India during the 1920s, stationed in Punjab and Sharakpur, where they engaged in agricultural and evangelistic work. See biographical information in first folder.
    - Handwritten diary of Verne Coapman, written in Wisconsin prior to missionary work, 1912 (Box 452, Folder 1)
    - Engagement announcement of Verne Coapman and Alice Lyon, 1920 (Box 452, Folder 2)
    - Handwritten diary of Coapman written in India, includes notes about hunting, gardens, travels, 1921 (Box 452, Folder 3)
    - Handwritten diary of Coapman from station in Sharakpur recounts evangelism work, and regarding schools and baptisms, 1922 (Box 452, Folder 4)
    - Handwritten diary of Coapman from India recounts travel, evangelism, baptisms, school activities, separation from family, 1923 (Box 452, Folder 5)
    - Handwritten diary of Coapman describes agricultural work, plague that killed many, move to Shahdara, visits to villages, his speaking schedule, 1924 Jan - 1927 Feb (Box 452, Folder 6)
    - Handwritten diary of Coapman from India describes home being built, family illnesses, travels, 1925 Jan - 1926 Apr (Box 452, Folder 7)
    - Brief diary notes written in U.S. following return from India; Coapman is pastoring a church, 1934 (Box 452, Folder 8)
    - Brief diary notes describe Coapman's church activities in U.S., 1936 (Box 452, Folder 9)
    - Brief diary notes describe Coapman's work in U.S., 1937 (Box 452, Folder 10)
    - Handwritten diary of Alice Coapman describes entering new work at Sharakpu; visiting villages and homes, teaching Bible stories, camping during ministry, child care, summer school, hospital visits, social activities, 1922-1923 (Box 452, Folder 11)
  - Coit, Thomas Winthrop
    1803 - Born in New London, CT; 1821 - Graduated from Yale College; 1823-24 - Attended Andover Theological Seminary; 1825 - Graduated from Princeton Theological Seminary; 1827-1834 - Ordained as Episcopal priest, served churches in Salem and Cambridge, MA; 1834-1837 - President of Transylvania University, KY; 1839-1849 - Served church in New Rochelle, NY; 1849-1854 - Professor at Trinity College, Hartford; 1854-1872 - Served church in Troy, NY; 1872-1885 - Professor at Berkeley Divinity School; 1885 - Died.
    - Bound volume of "rough draughts", 1880-1884 (Box 213)
  - Colwell, David Griffith
    Congregational minister, graduate of Yale College and YDS class of 1943.
    - Printed sermons, 1967 - 1975 Jan (Box 307)
      Material consists of 550 sermons and 117 lectures in audiocassette and printed format, from the period 1967-1988. One folder preceding the sermons and lectures contains a handwritten inventory listing each title chronologically.
    - Printed sermons, 1975 Jan - 1978 (Box 308)
    - Printed sermons, 1979-1982 (Box 309)
    - Audiocassettes of sermons, 1971-1973 Mar (Box 310)
    - Audiocassettes of sermons, 1973 Mar - 1974 Jun (Box 311)
    - Audiocassettes of sermons, 1974 Jun - 1975 Sep (Box 312)
    - Audiocassettes of sermons, 1975 Oct - 1988 (Box 313)
    - Audiocassettes of lectures: Bible lectures - 1978; "The Bible in the American Dream" - 1976; Bicentennial - 1976; Book reviews - 1973; Church Fathers - 1972; Exodus - 1977; Genesis - 1979-1980; Hosea - 1973; Isaiah, Second - 1973; Jeremiah - n.d.; John's Gospel - 1974; Luke - 1977; Mark - 1979;Mary - 1980; Parables - 1982; Post Nicene Fathers - n.d.; Psalms - 1974-1975; Revelation - 1975; Romans - 1981; Twentieth Century Theologians - 1981 (Box 314)
  - Colyer, Vincent
    Colyer (1825-1888) was a medical doctor during the Civil War.
    - "Record book of the Christian mission to the United States Army", 1861-1862 (Box 110)
  - Conn, Howard J.
    1911 Jun 19 - Born in Fresno, California; 1932 - B.A., Stanford University; 1932-1933 - Graduate studies in philosophy, Harvard; 1936 - B.D., Yale Divinity School; 1936-1941 - Associate Minister, Union Memorial Church, Glenbrook, CT; 1941-1944 - Minister, First Congregational Church, Great Barrington, MA; 1944-1976 -Senior Minister, Plymouth Congregational Church, Minneapolis, MN; 1976 - Minister Emeritus; 1980-1987 -Various interim pastorates in Michigan and Wisconsin.
    - More than 150 printed sermons and articles by Conn, dating from 1944 to 1986. A list of titles of the sermons and articles is available in the first folder. The last folder contains biographical information, tributes to Conn, and microfiche of Conn's manuscript sermons from the years 1936 to 1986. (Box 298–299)
  - Cooley, Frank
    1920 - Born; 1945 - Graduated from Yale Divinity School; Presbyterian missionary in China and Indonesia; Wrote widely re. the Indonesian church and Christian/Muslim relations.
    - Reports, workshops, notes, bulletin: All Indonesia Christian University Teachers Consultation, 1967 (Box 13)
    - Papers: Indonesia Academy of Sciences Seminar on Development, 1970 (Box 13)
    - National Congress Proceedings: Indonesia Student Christian Movement, 1967 (Box 13)
    - Notes and booklets, misc. :Indonesia Bible Society's Translation Consultation, 1968 (Box 13)
    - Material re. Semina Lembaga Pengabdian Mahasiswa Ekonomi (L.P.M.E.), 1969 (Box 13–14)
    - Material re. The Kalimantan Evangelical Church Synod Meeting, 1968 (Box 14)
    - Orientation for Missionaries:Preservice Orientation (1970); Inservice Orientation (1969), 1969-1970 (Box 14)
    - Material re. Christian higher education: Reports; Christian Universities of Indonesia (Box 14)
    - Material re. Christian higher education: Reports; Christian Universities of Indonesia, 1959-1972 (Box 15)
    - Collected material: R. McV.'s first draft on Colonel Untung (1967); Papers of Winburn Thomas (1955-1958); James C. McGilvray material (1966), 1955-1967 (Box 15)
    - Souvenir book from FC's time as YMCA missionary in China, which he had sent to his colleague Francis Fusan Zhao; tribute to FC by Zhao: "A Life of Witness to God' Love"; photo of FC, ca. 1948, 2005 (Box 385, Folder 1)
    - Paper by John A. Titaley: "Interpreting Frank L. Cooley's Legacy to Indonesia Christianity and Indonesia: From Colonialism to Liberation, 2009 (Box 455, Folder 16)
  - Coop, William
    Council Chair of the Presbyterian Church U.S.A. Bi-National Service program; colleague of Margaret Flory (YDSL Record Group No. 86). The Bi-National Service Council was created in 1970. Initially Bi-National Servants were U.S. individuals who had studied or served outside of the U.S. but membership was later expanded to include people from other countries who had served in mission or studied outside their home countries.
    - B-National Service Council minutes, 1980-2007 (Box 425, Folder 1-2)
    - Annual reports, directory of B-National Servants, 1984-1988, 1994 (Box 425, Folder 3-4)
    - Bi-National Servants' accounts of their work, 1992-1994 (Box 425, Folder 5-6)
    - Work Weeks in Puerto Rico, Indiana, Mexico, Switzerland (Box 425, Folder 7)
    - Proposals and reports, incl. "Toward the Internationalization of Theological Education", "Partnership, Mutualitiy, and Incarnational Solidarity", 1989-2007 (Box 425, Folder 8-9)
    - "Links" newsletter, 1984-1992 (Box 425, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 425, Folder 11)
    - Collected articles, 1994-1997 (Box 425, Folder 12)
  - Corey, Clara Watts Long
    1868 Jul - Born at Tenant's Harbor, Maine. Attended public schools through age 17. Also attended Cobwin Classical Institute, Waterford, Maine for one and a half years and Newton Theological Seminary for one year; 1894 - Married the Rev. Hebron Young Corey. H.Y. Corey was born in 1862 in New Brunswick. Taught for 12 years following 1 year of Normal School. Attended Acadia College. Started Student Volunteer Band at Acadia in 1890. Attended Newton Theological Seminary 1891 - 1894; 1894-1924 - Missionaries to India under the Maritime Baptists of Canada (1894-1912) and Canadian Baptist Foreign Mission (1912-1924). Lived in Telugu area, primarily in Vizianagram Cant and Bimlipatam. H.Y. Corey served as an evangelist and as principal of a high school. Children: Cedric, Albert, Charles, Elizabeth.
    - Approximately 150 letters (dating 1894-1900, 1910-1922, 1929) primarily from Clara in India to her mother in the United States. These letters are typed transcripts from the originals deposited at McMaster University. The letters deal primarily with the children and routine affairs of life for a missionary wife in India. Donor: Mrs. Elizabeth Jacks, Middlebury, CT (Box 287)
  - Corrie, Laura
    Laura Elizabeth Corrie (1818-1908) was born in India, the daughter of Daniel Corrie, who was the first Anglican Bishop of Madras and later President of the Church Missionary Society. Laura Corrie married George Bird in South Africa in 1835 and had several children.
    - A handwritten common place book compiled primarily in India (Calcutta in 1832, Madras in 1836 and 1837) and in South Africa (Cape Town in 1835)., 1832-1837 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      The volume is attributed to Laura Corrie but not signed by her. Entries include excerpts from works related to missionary work in India, biographies of queens of England, poems and articles relating to the death of Daniel Corrie (1777-1837, Bishop of Madras.
  - Craig, Ivy E.
    Craig was a missionary serving under the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions at the Mt. Selinda (Mt. Silinda) and Chicore mission stations in Southern Rhodesia during 1936-1953.
    - Letters from Craig to her sister Mildred and parents re. travel, etc., 1938 Apr- 1942 Jun (Box 453, Folder 1)
    - Circular letters from Craig describing her teaching activities at Mt. Selinda mission, 1936 Apr - 1938 Oct (Box 453, Folder 2)
    - Circular letters describing Craig's activites at Chikore and Craigmore, Southern Rhodesia, 1941 Apr - 1954 Sep (Box 453, Folder 3)
    - Writings: typescript story by Craig - "Norah Tamela", no date (Box 453, Folder 4)
    - Collected material: 4 issues of "East Africa Advance" newsletter of American Board Mission in Southern Rhodesia, 1937-1950 (Box 453, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook containing information about Southern Rhodesia, letters, magazine pictures, photographs, information re. Mt. Silinda hospital, maps, etc., compiled by Craig's sister, 1930s-1940s (Box 453, Folder 6)
  - Cumont, Franz Valery Marie
    1868 - Born; 1906 - Professeur a l'universite de Gand; 1909 - LL.D., University of Aberdeen; 1912 - LL.D., University of Brussels; 1920, 1921 - Silliman Memorial Lecturer at Yale; 1928 - Litt. D., Cambridge; 1929 - Litt. D., Trinity College, Dublin; 1947 - Died.
    - Printed writings (1897-1942, n.d.) including "Hypistos" (1897), "Notice sur un Attis Funeraire Decouvert a Vervox" (1901), "Pourquoi le latin fut la seule langue liturgique de l'Occident" (1904), etc. (Box 107)
  - Cunningham, W.D.
    Cunningham was an independent missionary in Japan, having been rejected for service by the Foreign Christian Missionary Society because of his health.
    - Circular letter from Cunningham in Yotsuya, Tokyo, and printed list of "Co-Workers", 1904, no date (Box 455, Folder 18)
  - Curtis, Edward Lewis
    1853 - Born; 1874 - B.A. Hanover College; 1886 - Ph.D., Honorary, Hanover College; 1891 - D.D., Yale; 1891-1911 - Holmes Professor of Hebrew, Yale; 1911 - Acting Dean of Yale Divinity School; 1911 - Died.
    - Letters of congratulations upon Curtis' Yale appointment (1891); two addresses and two article reprints by Curtis. (Box 103)
  - Curtiss, Zada A.
    Curtiss was a missionary under the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions in Kodaikanal, South India.
    - Two letters from Curtiss, one personal handwritten and one printed circular letter, written from Kodaikanal and Mangalapuram, Madura, 1912 (Box 455, Folder 17)
  - Cushman, Mary Floyd, M.D.
    Cushing was an ABCFM medical missionary in Ochileso, Angola, Portuguese West Africa, 1922-1942.
    - Three general letters to "Dear Friends" describing Cushman's arrival in Africa, her first Sunday in Africa, and her first "outstation trip", 1922-1923 (Box 329, Folder 3)
    - Personal letters from Mary Cushman to Lucille Toothaker, written from various places in the U.S., 1922-1929 (Box 329, Folder 4)
    - Personal letters from Mary Cushman to Lucille Toothaker, written from Africa, 1930 (Box 329, Folder 5)
    - Letters from Margaret Haven to Lucille Toothaker re. Mary Cushman, 1924-1931 (Box 329, Folder 6)
    - Biographical documentation: printed describing Cushman's work in Africa; leaflet from "Victorious Life Conferences" held in Keswick Grove, New Jersey, 1929, at which Cushman was a speaker, 1926, 1929 (Box 329, Folder 7)
  - Dahl, Nils Alstrup
    Dahl (1911-2001) was born and educated in Norway. He was Professor of New Testament at the University of Oslo from 1946 to 1965 and at Yale University from 1965 to 1980.
    - Articles and essays: "Anamnesis ("Ihukommelse") Som Motiv i de Nytestamentlige Skrifter og i den Eldste Kirke", Norsk Teologisk Tidsskrift: 1946; "The Atonement - An Adequate Reward for the Akeday (Ro 8:32)", Studies in honour of Matthew Black: 1969; "Benediction and Congratulation"; "Bibelutgaver i oldkirchen", Kirchens Arv-Kirkens Fremtid: July, 1968; "Conflicting Scriptural Passages in Tannaitic Exegesis - A Hermeneutical Rule and its Early Application", "Election and the People of God", Lutheran Quarterly: XXI, 1969; Der "Epheserbrief und der Verlorene, Erste Brief des Paulus an die Korinther", Abraham unser Vater --Festschrift für Otto Michel, 1963; "Erstgeborene Satans und der Vater des Teufels", Apophoreta --Festschrift für Ernst Haenchen, 1964, 1946, 1963-1969 (Box 420, Folder 1)
    - Articles and essays: "Eschatologie und Geschichte im Lichte der Qumrantexte", Zeit und Geschichte --Dankengabe an Rudolf Bultmann, 1964; "Eschatology and History in Light of the Qumran Texts", "Evangelium og plikt", Festskrift til Regin Prenter; "Form Critical Observations on the Early Preaching to the Church", "Der gekreuzigte Messias", Der historische Jesus und der kerygmatische Christus, 1960; "Hadde Bibelen Rett?" Kirke og Kultur, n.d.; "Hovedsak og bisetninger"; " Hva betyr Ev'ayyéhiov i Det Nye Testamente?", Svensk Teologisk Kvartalskrift: 1960; "Interpreting Ephesians:Then and Now", Theology Digest: Winter, 1977, 1960-1977, n.d. (Box 420, Folder 2)
    - Articles and essays: "The Johannine Church and History", Current Issues in New Testament Studies; "Kirkens intellektuelle dilemma", Minerva's Kvartalsskrift; "Kristus, Jødene og verden Etter Johannesevengeliet", Norsk Teologisk Tidsskrift 1959; "Kvinnelige Prester?" Kristen Humanism 1959; "Letter", Interpreter's Dictionary of the Bible: Supplementary Volume: "Manndraperen op hans far (Joh. 8:44)", Norsk Teologisk Tidsskrift: 1963; "Markusevangeliets sikte. Svensk Exegetisk Årsbok: 1957-58; "Det Menneskelige i Bibelen", Kirke og Kultur; "The Messiahship of Jesus in Paul", Studia Paulina: in honorem Johannis de Zwann, 1953; "Motsigelser i Skriften et gammelt hermeneutiskt problem", Svensk Teologisk Kvartalskrift: 1969, 1953-1969, n.d. (Box 420, Folder 3)
    - Articles and essays: "A New and Living Way: The Approach to God According to Hebrews 10:19-25. Interpretation; "New Testament Eschatology and Christian Social Action", Lutheran Quarterly: 1970; "New Testament Theology in a Pluralistic Setting", Reflection: April, 1980; "The Particularity of the Pauline Epistles as a problem in the Ancient Church", Neotestamentica et Patristica: Brill, 1962; "Paul (Letters)", "Paul and the Church at Corinth According to I. Cor. 1:10-4:21", Christian History and Interpretation: Studies Presented to John Knox: 1967, 1962-1980, n.d. (Box 420, Folder 4)
    - Articles and essays:"Paul's Letter to the Galatians", 105 pp.; "Paul's View of the Future of Israel.", 31 pp. (Box 420, Folder 5)
    - Articles and essays: "Paulus i Ekumenisk Perspektiv", Kirke og Kultur; "Paulus' syn pa Israels fremtid", Israel, Kirken og Verden. Nordisk telog-konferanse Utstein kloster: 1971; "Promise and Fulfillment in Paul", 13 pp; "Rettferdiggjo/relseslaerens Sosiologiske Funksjon og Konsekvenser", Norsk Teologisk Tidsskrift: 1964; "Ein Beitrag zum Problem Schrift und Tradition", Kommission I, "Die Bibel und die Botscahaft der Kirche an die Welt", Oekumenischer Rat der Kirchen, Jan. 1979; "A Short Commentary on the Epistle to the Ephesians", 50 pp.; "Social setting of the Doctrine of Justification", Reflection, 1966; "The Story of Abraham in Luke-Acts", Studies in Luke-Acts: Essays Presented in Honor of Paul Schubert: 1966, 1964-1979, n.d. (Box 420, Folder 6)
    - Articles and essays: "Tanker om Jødespørsmålet", Kirke og Kultur; "Die Theologie des Neuen Testaments", Theologische Rundschau, 1954; "Welche Ordnung der Paulusbriefe wird vom Muratorischen Kanon Vorausgesetzt?", Zeitschrift für die Neutestamentliche Wissenschaft: 1961; "Wellhausen on the New Testament", Semeia, 1954-1961, n.d. (Box 420, Folder 7)
    - Book reviews by NAD, 1946, n.d. (Box 420, Folder 8)
    - Course material: "The History of the Gospel Tradition: Extra-canonical texts" (Collected by Dahl for use in a New Testament seminar, Spring, 1979, Yale University (Box 420, Folder 9)
    - Society of Biblical Literature Paul Seminar: Participants, 1970 (Box 421, Folder 1)
    - Society of Biblical Literature Paul Seminar: Correspondence, 1970 Apr-1975 Aug (Box 421, Folder 2-6)
      Includes correspondence of Yale professor Abraham Malherbe, Dahl's associate in organizing the Paul Seminar
    - Society of Biblical Literature Paul Seminar: Meeting minutes, notes, papers, incl. by Boers, Doty, Stirewalt; "Galatians: Epistolary Genre, Content and Structure: Summary Theses" by NAD (1973), 1970-1975, n.d. (Box 421, Folder 7-10)
  - Dall, Charles Henry Appleton
    Dall (1816-1886) was an American Unitarian minister who became the first foreign missionary of the Unitarian Church in 1855. He established five schools in India and worked with Hindu social and cultural reformers.
    - Handwritten letter from Dall in Calcutta to Reverend George L. Chaney in Hawaii with enclosed newspaper clippings, 1877 May 27 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      Letter includes Dall's negative assessment of the Indian people with whom he is working. Clippings from Indian newspapers relate to missions and religion in India.
  - Dart family
    F. Sidney Dart was a missionary under the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions in the West Central Africa Mission. His father, Francis Dart, was an artist based in Oberlin, OH.
    - Letters from Sidney's father, Francis Henry Dart, re. life at home in Oberlin, OH, 1931 Aug - Dec (Box 452, Folder 31)
    - Letters from Sidney's children to their parents, 1931 Aug - Dec (Box 452, Folder 32)
    - Letters from and about Francis Dart, obituary, 1932-1936 (Box 452, Folder 33-37)
  - Davis, George H. and Billie
    The Davises were Assemblies of God missionaries in Latin America and the Caribbean, first appointed in 1957.
    - Two notebooks of George H. Davis containing poems written by him and by Billie, sermon notes, quotations. Missionary activity is not documented, no date (Box 453, Folder 8)
  - De Forest, Heman Packard
    839 Aug 20 - Born in North Bridgewater (now Brockton) MA; 1862 - Graduated from Yale College; 1866 - Graduated from Yale Divinity School; 1867 - Ordained; 1914 - Died.
    - Manuscript of 341 pages: "The Personal Life of Jesus, a study in Reality", 1913 (Box 94)
  - Dendy, Walter
    Rev. Dendy was a Baptist minister prominent in the work of the abolition of slavery in Jamaica.
    - Handwritten letter from Dendy in Falmouth, Jamaica to Rev. John Dyer, concerning Baptist congregations in Jamaica, 1834 September 15 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Denison, Robert Charles
    1868 Jul 22 - Born in Godfrey, IL; 1889 - A.B. Amherst College; 1892 - Graduated from Andover Theological Seminary; 1893-1897 - Congregational minister, Little Rock, Arkansas; 1897-1909 - Minister, Janesville, WI; 1909-1920 - Minister, United Church in New Haven, CT; 1919 - D.D. Amherst College; 1920 - Head of Philosophy Department, Pomona College, CA; 1936 - Died.
    - Printed writings: Five sermons (1910-1920); 2 poems (n.d.); "A Statement of Religious Belief" (Box 195)
    - Typescript writings: Prayers (1911-1912); Two sermons (Box 195)
    - Biographical material - includes photographs, 1909-1936 (Box 195)
  - Dey, Basanti
    An Indian Christian, daughter of Rev. Nar Dey of Patna
    - Photograph album assembled by Basanti Dey on behalf of John Measures documenting a trip to visit mission in India 1955-1956. (Box 28, Folder 1)
      Mr. Measures was apparently a solicitor working on behalf of the Church of England. Photos document missions, churches, and staff of the Church of England in Bombay, Allahabad, Amritsar, Lahore, Madras, Alleppey, Kottayam, Calcutta, and elsewhere.
  - Dinsmore, Charles Allen
    1860 - Born; 1884 - B.A., Dartmouth; 1888 - B.D., YDS; 1888-1890 - Congregational minister, Whitneyville, CT; 1890-1895 - Pastorate in Willimantic ,CT; 1895-1905 - Pastorate at Phillips Church, Boston; 1903-1904 - Alumni Lecturer, Yale Divinity School; 1905-1920 - Pastorate in Waterbury, CT; 1906 - D.D., Dartmouth; 1916 - D.D., Yale; 1941 - Died.
    - Correspondence: Primarily personal in nature, 1868-1939 (Box 97)